SRAVAN KUMAR KILARU

Detroit, MI • (806)-368-2521

kilarusravankumar@gmail.com

www.github.com/kilarusravankumar

www.linkedin.com/in/sravankilaru

Analytical professional with hands-on experience in system development, applications programming, and website management. Solid foundation in managing development projects and mentoring team members, while implementing various technologies. Ambitious engineer with the demonstrated ability to quickly learn new technologies and adapt to changing environments.

Technical Proficiencies

Languages:	JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Java, GoLang, MongoDB, MYSQL and IBM DB2
Frameworks/Libraries:	AngularJS, React, Express, Spring, jQuery, and Node.js.
DevOps Technologies:	Git, GitLab, GitSwarm, Jira, Jenkins, Docker, and Bamboo

Professional Experience

University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI

Oct 2018 - Present

App Programmer/Analyst

Build and maintain a PHI data platform by utilizing Go, docker, and MongoDB for the department of pathology. Rendered analytical support in maintaining and upgrading existing department of pathology website using React and PHP.

- Designed and deployed scalable web applications by using React SSR for the University of Michigan and vendors.
- Supported team members in pathology specimen tracking tool built by using react, Node, Express, web Sockets, and docker.

Mercedes-Benz Financial Services, Detroit, MI

Oct 2017 - Oct 2018

Java Developer

Redesigned and Rewrote existing Mainframe batch jobs in java 8. Created and rolled out the Maven Build process to existing title management utility applications.

- Ensured the successful migration of Mercedes-Benz Car's title management application to J2EE 7 with a new user interface built by utilizing Html5, CSS3, and jQuery as well as deployed the application in Websphere application server 9 (liberty).
- Produced lease end maturity bill by aligning web services and batch processes.

PowerSchool Inc, Folsom, CA

March 2017 - Aug 2017

Web Developer

Guaranteed the seamless running of processes by using Git and GitSwarm for version control systems. Programmed Java classes as well as implemented Business Delegate Factory pattern and Hibernate, Struts, MYSQL, and SQL Server.

- Transformed 50% UI of legacy application to suit user needs better with JavaScript, jQuery, and JSP.
- Reshaped and deployed the UI for Powerschool web platform modules.

Pegasys Information Technologies, Novi, MI

April 2015 – Feb 2017

Web Developer

Coded and designed the layout of a website according to a company's specifications. Developed websites by using various technologies.

- Utilized AngularJS, Sass, and HTML5 for the development of 100% responsive UI and single-page applications.
- Structured and updated server by utilizing Express and Node.js to manage and expose REST web services.

Education

Master's in computer science, Northwest Missouri State University, Maryville, MO, Dec 2015

Bachelor's in Computer Science and Engineering, GITAM University, Hyderabad, India, April 2014